<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>Omar Olivares Urrutia</title><description>I&#39;m a Software Engineer with a strong background in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) who loves turning complex ideas into practical solutions. I&#39;ve worked as an AI Engineer, Developer Relations Engineer, and freelance content creator, crafting engaging AI-focused content. I&#39;ve helped build AI-powered products such as Kilo Code (an autonomous coding agent), Emergent Mind (a RAG system for CS research), and a range of scalable web applications for early-stage startups.</description><link>https://olivares.cl/</link><atom:link href="https://olivares.cl/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Omar Olivares Urrutia</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/ofou/ofou.github.io</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 03:09:25 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 03:09:25 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.17.3</generator> <image> <url>None</url> <title>Omar Olivares Urrutia</title><link>https://olivares.cl/</link> </image> <item> <title>Learning in 2025</title> <author>Omar Olivares</author> <category>Books</category> <description>This year, my focus is on exploring the intersection of neuroscience and AI. I&#39;ll be diving deep into textbooks and hands-on projects to better understand both the human brain and artificial intelligence. The following lists outline the books, textbooks, and codebases that I&#39;m currently reading and coding from.</description><link>https://olivares.cl/blog/2024/01/01/learning-in-2025/</link> <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 01:45:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://olivares.cl/feed_rss_updated.xml">Omar Olivares Urrutia</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://olivares.cl/blog/2024/01/01/learning-in-2025/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Jiro Dreams of Sushi</title> <author>Omar Olivares</author> <category>Films</category> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/es/title/tt1772925/&#34;&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&lt;/a&gt;, and I was really amazed by the quality of the documentary. I resonate highly with Jiro&#39;s philosophy and work ethic, and I think that his story is a great reminder that anyone can achieve greatness if they&#39;re willing to put in the time and effort. I think his insights are applicable to anyone in any field, not just sushi chefs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a collection of quotes from a follow-up interview with Jiro and his son, Yoshikazu. Now that everyone is trying to &lt;em&gt;cook&lt;/em&gt; at work, I think these insights are more relevant than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://olivares.cl/blog/2025/05/01/jiro-dreams-of-sushi/</link> <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:05:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://olivares.cl/feed_rss_updated.xml">Omar Olivares Urrutia</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://olivares.cl/blog/2025/05/01/jiro-dreams-of-sushi/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>